### Mohammad Affan Sheikh

Versatile, Dynamic, Quick learner, Enthusiastic

### **SUMMARY**

Enthusiastic Civil Engineer with more than 2 year 9 months of experience as a site engineer skilled in Site Engineering, BBS, quantity surveying, Quality Checks, supervision and labor management. Having good interpersonal and communication skills with leadership qualities. Looking for roles of Civil Site Engineer, Project Engineer or Quantity Surveyor.

### **EXPERIENCE**

BLUE BIRD INFRASTRUCTURE, Nagpur MH, India

**Designation - Project Engineer.** 

May 2021 - Till Date

Project Name: Dr. Babasaheb Ambedkar Magaswargiya Sootgirni (Textile Mill), Phase II-D Block, MIDC, Butibori, Maharashtra, India.

Project Details : Construction Area of 96,000 Sq.ft Industrial Construction Project Cost of ₹24 Crores.

### **Roles & Responsibilities:**

- Review architectural plans and prepare quantity needs of items and their respective costs.
- Liaise with Clients, Architect, Subcontractor and Suppliers for timely completion of the works before the agreed deadlines.
- Carrying out on site operations, Inspection according to Cad drawings, estimation and costing of various materials.
- To provide the main Contractor the daily progress report of the works achieved and discuss with him the planned works for the next day.
- Collaborating with the procurement department to ensure timely availability of necessary materials required at site.
- Studying and assessing the drawings, Plans and specifications and other documents relating to the project.
- Quantity Surveying and preparing BOQ.
- Leading, directing and monitoring the performance of all site Foremen, Supervisors and support staff in the team.

## Build Fields, Nagpur, MH, India— Site Engineer MARCH 2020 - MAY 2021

- Coordinate and direct construction workers and subcontractors.
- Providing technical advice and suggestion for improvement on particular projects.



affans175@gmail.com +91 7066938687 https://www.linkedin .com/in/affan-sheikh-1499a7125

Skype:

live:.cid.e672220c6a4

440f1

### **SKILLS**

**Autocad Architecture** 

MS Office

MS Excel

**Etabs** 

**Revit Architecture** 

**Quantity Survey** 

Site Engineering & Coordination

Interpersonal & Organizational

### **PERSONAL DETAILS**

DOB : 12th Jan 1998 Nationality : Indian Marital Status : Single

### **LANGUAGES**

English Hindi Urdu

- Work closely with subcontractors on project progress and ensure timely work arrangements
- Liaising with Architect and design team to achieve the highest achievable standards within the contract.
- Carryout quality inspection on-site and ensure the quality of work to be completed on scheduled time.
- Properly control the use of resources at the site and ensure all necessary resources and materials are availed.

## Sheeza Constructions , Nagpur MH, India— Supervisor May 2019 - March 2020

- Supervise all architectural works and ensure all works are carried out in accordance with approved specifications.
- Checking quality of workmanship and materials at site.
- Ensuring proper checking of contractors bills.
- Checked construction work on day to day basis.
- Planning and scheduling monthly weekly/monthly targets for contractor at site reviewing works on constant basis.

### **EDUCATION**

# Anjuman College Of Engineering And Technology, Nagpur — Civil Engineering

AUGUST 2015 - JUNE 2019

- Bachelor's degree in Civil Engineering
- CGPA: 8.2/10

### St. Francis De Sales, Nagpur — HSC

May 2015

Scored 59.23%

## St. John's High School, Nagpur — SSC

JUNE 2013

• Scored 78.55%

### **CERTIFICATES**

• Diploma in Building Design.

### **PERSONAL SKILLS**

Strong

Communication

Teamwork

Hardworking

**Problem Solving** 

Quick learner

Attention to detail

Consistent